Minato's Death
（ミナト）乱世を利用して
生き延びてきた→
Many shinobi from small villages
that survived
小さな里の忍たちには→
by taking advantage
of the turbulent situation,
火　風　土の三里の支配を
望まぬ者たちも多い。
have no wish to be controlled by
the nations of Fire, Wind and Earth.
これからもさまざまな
揺さぶりをかけてくるだろう。
There's no doubt they will continue
to cause disruptions.
しかし　多くの犠牲の上に
実現した平和は→
But we must maintain peace,
which was attained through
the sacrifice of many.
守り抜かなければならない。
そこでキミたちの力
頼りにさせてもらうよ。
I'm counting on all of you.
（みんな）はっ！
– Yes, sir!
PRACTICE FIELD THREE
（カカシ）千鳥！
Chidori!
Huh?
忍　５人急速接近！
Five shinobi,
all approaching rapidly!
額当ては？
岩隠れだ。
What does their headband show?
The Hidden Stone.
条約を結んでる里だろ？
何か緊急の用件でも？
We have a peace treaty
with them, don't we?
Maybe they have urgent business?
What?!
なぜ条約を破る？
Why are you breaking the treaty?!
我々は　木ノ葉隠れだ！
We're the Leaf Village!
何かの間違いではないのか？
You must be making a mistake!
Reinforcements! Withdraw!
新手だ！　引け！
助かった。　岩隠れの裏切りだ。
Thanks for saving us!
The Hidden Stone betrayed us!
岩隠れの手裏剣ではない。
This isn't a Hidden Stone shuriken.
ニセ者か？　なんのために？
So they were fakes? But why?
岩と木ノ葉を分裂させる気だ。
They want to cause a rift between
the Stone and the Leaf.
あっ　おい！
H-Hey!
深追いはするな！
Don't chase them too far!
（カカシ）千鳥！
Chidori!
（ガイ）よお！　元気か？
Hey! How have you been?
シカトかよ！
Are you ignoring me?!
カカシが暗部に編入されて
まだ　わずかな日数ですが→
It's only been a short while since
Kakashi transferred into the ANBU,
その働きには
目を見張るものがあります。
but some of his actions
are quite astonishing.
うむ…。
１人。
One…
うわっ！
４人！
Four!
うわっ！
写輪眼！　お前がウワサの冷血カカシか。
Sharingan!
You're Cold-blooded Kakashi
that everyone talks about!
待て　カカシ！
Wait, Kakashi!
ひぃ～　助けてくれ！
Help me!
５人！
Five!
５人とも急所を一撃だな。
All five were killed with a single blow
to their vital points.
１人くらい残しておけば
情報が手に入ったものを。
If you kept at least one alive,
we could've gotten intel…
火影様が心配されていた→
Lord Hokage, regarding the issue
that you were concerned about…
リンを手にかけたことによる
心的外傷の兆候は見られません。
We have not seen any evidence of
psychological trauma in Kakashi
associated with taking Rin's life.
何か気になることでも？
いや。
Is something on your mind?
No…
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
おめでとう。
Congratulations.
（クシナ）えっ！？
What?
予定日は…　そう　１０月１０日。
Your due date is…let's see…
October 10.
だってばね！
Oh then, yeah!
えっ！？　赤ちゃんが？
Huh? A baby…?
私　母親になるんだってばね。
I'm going to be a mother, ya know!
俺が　父親になる…。
And I'm going be a father…
母親だってばね！
A mother, ya know!
父親になるんだ…。
I'm going to be a father!
母親だってばね！
A mother, ya know!
これで　俺も父親か！
Imagine that,
I'm going to be a father!
私は母親だってばね。
A mother, ya know!
（ミナト）カカシ　今の任務を離れ
特別任務についてもらう。
Kakashi, I want you to leave
your current mission
and take on a special mission.
何か問題でも？
そういうことじゃないよ。
Was there an issue?
It's nothing like that.
ただ　これは
極秘扱いなんだけど…。
It's more like a top-secret errand.
クシナに子供ができたんだ。
Kushina's pregnant!
Oh… Congratulations.
えっ！？
あ…　おめでとうございます。
Thank you.
ありがとう。　しかし
人柱力の女性が妊娠すると→
But when a female Jinchuriki
becomes pregnant,
the energy that keeps the seal
in place transfers to the fetus,
封印に使っているエネルギーが→
お腹の子供へと
移行していくので→
尾獣の封印が弱まる傾向にある。
weakening the Tailed Beast seal.
そこでだ
出産までの約１０か月の間→
And so…it will be roughly
ten months until she gives birth.
何事もないように
キミにクシナの警護を頼みたいんだ。
I want you to guard Kushina
against any incidents.
はい。
Yes, sir!
（ミナト）クシナの護衛任務　お疲れさま。
Thank you for protecting Kushina.
（カカシ）しかし　まだ…。
But…
出産行事に関しては
三代目直属の暗部が→
It's standard for the ANBU
directly under Lord Third
to take over the guard
during the birthing period.
護衛についてくれることに
なっているんだ。
では　再び暗部の任務に戻ります。
Then I'll be returning to
my duties in ANBU.
まっ　そんなに慌てなくても…。
There's no need to be so hasty.
しばらく　休暇を取るといい。
Why don't you take
a break for a while?
RIN NOHARA
すまない
しばらく来られなくて。
I'm sorry I haven't been by.
決して
忘れようとしていたわけじゃ…。
It's not that I've forgotten…
これ　一応　極秘扱いなんだけど→
I've been…sworn to secrecy…
ミナト先生のお子さんが
生まれるんだってさ。
but Minato Sensei is going
to be a father.
戦争を知らない世代だよ。
This generation won't know war.
俺たちも　もう少し遅くに…。
If only we were born a little later…
RIN NOHARA
オビトにも報告してやらなくちゃ。
I should tell Obito too.
もう行くよ　リン。
So I'll be going, Rin.
毎度あり！
おう　また来るよ。
Thank you!
Thanks, I'll come again.
ほら　しっかり歩けって…
おっとっと！
Hey! Watch where you're walking.
う～ん…　今日もジャンケンで
いいんじゃない？
Why don't we just do
Rock-Paper-Scissors again tonight?
またそれか。
もっと熱い勝負はないのか？
Not that again!
Think of something more exciting!
それでも俺のライバルなのか？
How can you call yourself my rival?!
明日も早いんだし
今日は　ナシということで。
We have an early start tomorrow.
So let's pass for tonight.
任務を言い訳にするな！
Don't use a mission
as an excuse!
この熱く燃え盛る　溢れんばかりの
パワーを持て余している今こそ→
I have all this hot pent-up
energy inside me!
Now is the time for
diligent training!
日々の鍛錬に精進する！
その地道な努力の
積み重ねこそが→
Honest-to-goodness discipline
and hard work
未来の任務の成功に
つながる…。
lead to success in future missions!
人の話を聞け！
Are you listening to me?!
お前　暗部に入ってから
冷たいんじゃないか？
You've gotten awfully cold
since joining the ANBU.
冷血って呼ばれてるウワサは
聞いているぞ！
I've heard the gossip.
They're calling you cold-blooded.
いや　わかってる。
Well, I know that
I'm not supposed to talk
暗部のことは
口外できないってことはな。
about your being in the ANBU.
だからといって
俺とのつきあいを忘れるな！
Still, that's no reason to forget
about our friendship!
青春は短いんだ！
それより　ガイ…。
Youth is short!
Say, Guy…
何か変な感じしないか？
Do you sense anything weird?
さっきから空気が冷たいような…。
There's been a chill in the air…
そうしたのは　お前の態度だ！
It's your attitude that's causing it!
青春は　今しかないんだぞ！
There's nothing like
the present for youth!
（イタチ）何だ？　この感じ。
What is this…feeling?
よしよし。
There, there…
《イヤな感じだ。
こんなときにかぎって→
It's a strange feeling.
Of all times for
Mom and Dad to be out…
父さんと母さんが
出かけてるなんて…》
泣くな　サスケ。
Don't cry, Sasuke.
何があっても　お兄ちゃんが
絶対　守ってあげるからな。
No matter what happens,
your big brother will
definitely protect you…
（ヒルゼン）まさかのう…。
It can't be…
（マダラ）口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
（みんな）うわぁ～！
あ　あれは…。
That's…!
N-No way…
ま　まさか…。
九尾！
The Nine Tails!
– Run! Help!
– It's the Nine Tails!
やれ　九尾！
Go, Nine Tails!
三代目火影様！
Lord Third!
九尾が…
九尾が里に出現しました！
The Nine Tails is…!
The Nine Tails has suddenly
appeared in the village!
おのれ　九尾！
Damn you, Nine Tails!
今こそ燃えたぎるパワーを
解き放つとき！
This is the moment I release
my fiery pent-up power!
早まるな　ガイ。
かかってこい！
Don't be hasty, Guy!
Come on! I'll be your opponent!
俺が相手だ！
待て！
Wait!
Huh?
お前たちは今すぐ
詰め所に集まれ！
Gather immediately in the guardroom!
なぜです？
先代様からの命令だ。
Why?
It's the Third Hokage's orders!
ヒルゼン様が？
Lord Hiruzen?
そういうことだ。　行くぞ　ガイ！
You heard him. Let's go, Guy!
BIND
いいか？　お前ら若い世代は
九尾に近づくな。
Now listen up.
You young shinobi are to
stay away from Nine Tails.
（紅）どういうこと？
What do you mean by that?
これは　他里との戦争ではなく
里内のゴタゴタだ。
This is not a battle between villages…
This is a domestic issue.
お前たちが
命をかけるものではない。
There is no reason for you
all to risk your lives.
勝手なことを言うな！
Speak for yourself!
落ち着け　紅！
Calm down, Kurenai!
お前だって忍だ。
You're a shinobi too.
いつまでも
生きていられるわけじゃない。
We are not guaranteed
to live a long life.
だが　娘よ　お前は　せめて→
But, my daughter,
you are a woman.
At least, pass on the Will of Fire
to my grandchild.
わしの孫となる子に
火の意志を託せ！
それを父との約束にしてくれ。
Make that your oath to your father….
お前を信頼しているぞ。
For I do believe in you.
This is no time for a family argument!
親子ゲンカをしている場合か！
うう　こんなとき
何もできないなんて口惜しいな！
I can't take not being able to do
anything at a time like this!
結界が消えた！
The barrier has disappeared!
四代目！
Lord Fourth!
クシナ様！
Lady Kushina!
すぐ　木ノ葉病院に！
医療忍者を集めよ。
Take her to Leaf Hospital immediately!
Summon the Medical Ninja!
三代目…。
Lord Third…
クシナ！
Kushina…!
Please take care…
その子を
よろしく…　お願いします。
of the child.
ああ　何も心配はいらん。
Of course, you don't need to worry.
（クシナ）名前は…　ナルト。
His name is…
Naruto…
ミナトと私が　自来也先生の
小説からとって　決めた名前です。
Minato and I…
picked it from…
Jiraiya Sensei's novel…
ナルトだな　わかった！
わしが責任をもつ。
Naruto, you say?
Fine. I take full responsibility.
だから　この子のために
もう黙っておれ。
So, for the child's sake,
you must rest!
クシナ…　必ず！
Kushina! I promise…
ミナト…　クシナよ。
Minato…
Kushina…
お前たちは命をかけて
木ノ葉隠れの里を→
You both gave your lives…
to protect the Hidden Leaf Village…
and its future.
そして　その未来を守ってくれた。
《ミナト先生…》
Minato Sensei…
（ホムラ）九尾は撃退したものの→
We repelled the Nine Tails,
そのための犠牲は
あまりにも大きかった。
but the sacrifice was much too great.
（コハル）悲しんでばかりはおられぬ。
急がねばならぬのは→
This is no time to lament.
The Hokage's seat is empty.
We must decide on someone quickly.
空席になってしまった
火影を決めることじゃ。
（シカク）ミナトの次の世代に任せるのは
いかがでしょう？
Perhaps someone from
the age group below Minato?
優秀な上忍は育っているが→
We have nurtured fine jonin,
but they all lack the experience
to rule over a village.
まだ　皆をまとめるには
経験不足の感は否めない。
では　他に誰が？
Is there anyone else?
Well…
やむをえぬ。　非常時だ。
It cannot be helped.
This is a critical time.
このヒルゼンが引き受ける。
I shall take over.
Oh, will you do that?
おう　やってくれるか？
うむ　そうしてくれるなら。
If you are willing…
You stepped down once…
Are you up to the task?
（ダンゾウ）一度　火影の座を譲った身に
務まりますかな？
事実　九尾出現に
駆けつけていながら→
Truth be told, even though
you went after the Nine Tails,
四代目を救い出すことも
かなわなかったのでは？
you failed to save the Fourth Hokage…
それは　酷な言いぐさじゃ。
That remark is uncalled for.
あのとき
ダンゾウこそ　どこにいたのじゃ？
And where were you
at that time, Danzo?
ハハハハハ！
年寄りの冷や水よ。
Just indulge this old man.
Let me fill in as Hokage until
we can groom the next one.
次の火影が育つまでの
つなぎということで→
納得してもらえぬか？
はたけカカシだね？
ダンゾウ様…。
Kakashi Hatake, correct?
Lord Danzo…
Come and work under me.
What do you say?
どうだ？
わしのもとで働いてみないか？
But…I was Minato Sensei's…
しかし　俺はミナト先生の…。
Lord Fourth, the one
who recruited you into the ANBU
お前を暗部に誘った四代目は
もうこの世にいない。
is no longer with us.
このままでは　返り咲く三代目の
直属の部下として→
If you stay where you are,
you will end up working
directly under the Third
who will reassume his position.
働くことになる。
平和主義の三代目こそ
いたずらに戦争を引き延ばし→
It was his foolhardy ideals of peace
that dragged the war on
オビトやリンを死に追いやった
張本人と言えるのだぞ。
and drove Obito and Rin
to their deaths.
But…
ですが…。
それに→
Furthermore, on the night
of the Nine Tails' rampage,
あの九尾襲来の夜
三代目が出した命により→
you were not able to join the fight
because of Lord Third's orders…
お前たちは九尾との戦いに
加わることができなかった。
Isn't that why Lord Fourth
lost his life?
それゆえ　四代目が命を失うことに
なったのではないか？
まさか　自分が返り咲くための
謀略とは思いたくないが。
I don't want to believe that
he planned this to return to power…
but the future of the Hidden Leaf
cannot be entrusted to someone like him.
あんなヤツに木ノ葉の未来を
預けるわけにはいかん。
火の国の大名府への道中は→
A few ANBU will be selected to
暗部から数人だけを選抜し
護衛にまわす。
guard the Feudal Lord's procession
back to his prefecture.
（みんな）はっ！
これが計画書だ。
木遁？
木遁大樹林の術！
（ダンゾウ）待て！
この者は　わしが呼んだ。
はっ！
よく来てくれたな。
これを。
ついに時が来た。
でかしたぞ　カカシ。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。